# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道甜品
In this video I'm going to share a dessert with you.
# 拔丝红薯
Basi ("Silk-Pulling") Candied Sweet Potato
# 首先我们准备红皮黄心薯600克
First let's prepare 600 grams of red-skinned sweet potatoes.
# 去皮之后切成大小均匀的滚刀块备用
Peel the skin and cut into evenly sized pieces.
# 同学们红薯的种类不受限制可以自由选择
Feel free to choose from different variety of sweet potatoes.
# 切好之后放入盆中用清水清洗干净备用
After cutting, put them in a pot and rinse with water.
# 红薯和土豆类似会因为淀粉氧化变黑
Sweet potatoes are similar to potatoes in that the surface starch will oxidize and turn black.
# 所以必须用清水淘洗一遍
That's why it's better to wash them with water.
# 清洗干净之后捞出下一步开始准备初加工
Once washed, drain them and prepare for blanching.
# 锅中加入适量的清水
Add some water to the wok.
# 然后加入切好的红薯下锅焯水3分钟备用
Then add the sweet potato and blanch for 3 minutes.
# 这一步的目的是提前将红薯断生
The purpose of this step is to par-cook the sweet potato.
# 防止下锅炸的时候表面熟心里生
So that it cooks evenly throughout when deep fried.
# 红薯断生之后捞出凉水冲冷
After blanching the sweet potatoes, strain them out and rinse them with cold water.
# 控干水分之后加入适量的玉米淀粉上粉
After draining, add some cornstarch to the sweet potato.
# 上淀粉的目的是让红薯锁住中间的水分
The purpose of the starch is to lock in the moisture.
# 从而达到外酥里嫩口感上乘
The result would be crispy on the outside and tender on the inside.
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Start preparing the other ingredients next.
# 碗中加入适量的白砂糖备用（200克）
Add some sugar in a bowl (200g)
# 然后加入等量的清水搅拌均匀备用
Then add equal amount of water and mix well.
# 下一步开始制作
Start cooking next.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First let's heat up the wok.
# 锅烧热之后加入“小宽油”
When the wok is hot, add "small broad oil".
# 油温5成热之后加入处理好的红薯
When the oil temperature reaches 50% (150 °C), add the processed sweet potatoes.
# 然后转中小火将其炸5分钟
Then turn the heat to medium-low and fry for 5 minutes.
# 同学们切记不能开太大火否则很容易炸糊
Remember not to turn up the heat too much or it will easily burn.
# 且后半段的时候应该开小火浸炸使其中间熟透
And the second half of the frying process should be done over low heat so that the center is cooked through.
# 5分钟之后捞出红薯下一步开始炒糖拔丝
After 5 minutes, remove the sweet potatoes from the wok and start prepping the sugar next.
# 锅中加入调好的白糖水
Add the sugar water mixture to the wok.
# 开小火将白糖熬化
Use low heat to melt the sugar.
# 熬制起大泡的时候加入适量的白醋
Add a bit of white vinegar when the sugar is bubbling.
# 加白醋的目的是让糖丝拉得更长（保守超过1米以上）
The purpose of adding white vinegar is to make the "sugar silk" stretch longer (over 1 meter).
# 中途再加入适量的食用盐定味
Add some salt to adjust the taste.
# 待糖浆开始起小泡的时候再加入适量的植物油一起翻炒拌匀
When the bubbles turn small, add some vegetable oil and mix well.
# 这一步的目的是加速糖浆变化
The purpose of this step is to accelerate the caramelisation.
# 也可以使糖浆冷却之后减少粘连容易洗锅
It also reduces the sticking of the sugar after cooling and makes it easier to wash the wok.
# 待糖浆变成类似香油的淡黄色之后即可拔丝
When the sugar turns slightly golden (sesame oil color), it's ready for the "silk pulling".
# 此时立刻将炸好的红薯下锅翻炒均匀即可出锅装盘
At this point, immediately put the fried sweet potatoes in the wok and mix well before serving.
# 我们来开始检验拔丝的效果
Let's see how well the "silk" pulls.
# 下面开始技术总结
Let's start the technical summary.
# 第一
First,
# 拔丝选用的糖最好是纯度高且容易在水中化开
The best sugar for "silk pulling" has high purity and dissolves easily in water.
# 第二
Second,
# 红薯必须提前焯水处理否则中间很难炸熟炸透
Sweet potatoes must be blanched in advance or it is difficult to deep fry them thoroughly.
# 第三
Third,
# 糖水炒化起大泡的时候加入白醋能够让糖丝更有韧劲
Adding white vinegar when the sugar bubbles makes it more elastic.
# 而且在拔丝的时候不容易断且拉得更长更细
Which will help the sugar stretch longer and thinner.
# 第四
Fourth,
# 糖浆冷却之后一般会很难处理
Once the sugar cools, it's usually difficult to clean.
# 如果加入适量的植物油之后会减小糖的粘连
If you add some vegetable oil during the process, it will reduce the sugar's stickiness.
# 下面开始成品展示
Let's have a look at the finished dish.